-太美味了  -韭葱的味道会不会太呛
- Wonderful. - ‭Are the leeks too overpowering?
一点也不
Not at all.
和我们在佛罗伦萨吃的一样棒
That's as good ‭as the one we had in Florence.
-别讨好我  -我没有
- All right, don't humor me. ‭- I'm not.
排练得如何
How was rehearsal?
那女的有好好表现吗
Did what's-her-name behave herself?
她觉得整个章节都是她的似的
She takes the whole section for granted.
我还在纠结要不要跟她说
I'm debating ‭whether to say something.
你该说出来  真的
I think you should, absolutely.
别憋在心里
Don't keep it inside.
准备放菜丝了吗
Ready for the chiffonade?
好  谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
毕竟  如果她影响了整个表演...
And after all, if she's compromising the work...
这很难说
Mm. Well, it's debatable.
舒伯特那部分还不错
I mean, the Schubert is coming along nicely.
主要是士气的问题
It's more about morale.
士气会影响质量
Morale can affect quality.
天知道霍华德是如何赴汤蹈火
God knows the hoops that Howard jumps through
-才让员工士气昂扬的  -的确
- just to keep the troops humming. - ‭Well, true.
该给你颁个奖
You deserve a medal for this.
没什么大不了的
Please. It's no big deal.
这是你的酱油泡姜腌汁吗
Your soy-ginger marinade?
我看到个柠檬的好像还挺好吃
Well, I found a citrus one that looked good,
所以我想试试
so I thought I would try that.
总之  你是个勤劳且毫无怨言的人
Well, anyway, you are a trouper.
我道歉在先
I apologize in advance.
他是...需要慢慢适应才会喜欢上的那种人
Let's just say he's... something of an acquired taste.
他能有多糟糕呢
Oh, how bad can he be?
以防万一吧  我们先约个暗号
Well, just in case, let's have a high sign.
卡洛尔·伯纳特招牌动作如何
How about ‭the old Carol Burnett thing?
美国女演员
她拉耳垂的动作吗
Oh, where she pulls her earlobe?
没错
Exactly.
你做这个动作  我就会说我还要读报告
You do this, and I'll say I have briefs to read,
-然后我们就能摆脱他  -好  就随你意
- and we'll get rid of him. - All right. Whatever you want.
你知道她为什么拉耳朵吗  卡洛尔·伯纳特
You know why she did that -- Carol Burnett?
有趣的故事  那是给她奶奶打的暗号
It's a great story. It was a signal to her grandmother,
她将她抚养长大...
who had raised her, as --
没搞错吧
Seriously?
他来早了
He's early.
你真可爱
You're a doll.
我的天  看看这地方
Holy shit. Look at this place.
吉米  欢迎
Hey, Jimmy, thanks for coming.
抱一个
Bring it on in here.
给你带了点家乡味
Hey! ‭Little taste of home for you.
老风格啤酒
找遍了城里的商店才买到的
Had to look all over town to find a place that had it.
来不及包装
‭Didn't have time to wrap it.
谢谢
Well, thanks.
可以了
You're good.
好
Yeah.
我在找地方落脚
I'm looking for a place.
最近都住在华美达酒店
Been staying at the Ramada.
对了  感谢你帮忙
And thanks for the help, by the way.
我已经找到几个中意的地点
I've found a few that I like.
有个带泳池的地方
This one place, ‭the beachcomber, has a pool.
因为我们麦吉尔家的人
And since the Mcgill clan
皮肤简直比白鼠还白
is whiter ‭than a pack of albino rats...
我觉得我该晒晒黑了
‭...I figure I better start working on my tan.
所以我真觉得那个地方不错
So, seriously considering that option.
我强烈建议涂防晒油
I strongly suggest sunscreen.
我们这儿可是海拔一千五百米
We're up about 5,000 feet here.
你会晒伤的
You'll fry.
好主意  防晒油...  打勾
Excellent point. Sunscreen -- check.
你是...小提琴家
So... A violinist?
听查克说  你非常有天赋
And according to Chuck, a crazy talented one at that.
真佩服
Mm. ‭I mean, wow.
查克过奖了
Well, Chuck is very gracious.
她又谦虚了
She's being modest.
丽贝卡在同行中备受尊敬
Rebecca is widely respected amongst her peers.
马友友还参加了我们的婚礼
‭Yo-yo Ma came to our wedding.
华裔大提琴家
这真的...
That's, um...
棒极了
Right on, man.
说到你们婚礼
About the wedding, um,
我一直想道歉
I've been meaning ‭to apologize...about that.
-我真的很抱歉没能  -不要紧的
- I am truly sorry I wasn't... - No worries, please.
说说在哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的第一周吧
So, tell us about your first week at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
很棒啊
It was great.
我被安排在收发室工作
I mean, they got me working in the mailroom, which
万事开头难嘛
you gotta start somewhere.
我学会了用静电复印机
I learned how to use the Xerox machine,
惊人得复杂
which is surprisingly complicated.
以前按下一个按键  弹出一张纸
I mean, press a button, a piece of paper spits out --
现在不一样了
Not anymore. ‭Mm.
这机器简直是台电脑
Thing's practically a computer.
简直像宇宙飞船一样
It's like goddamn space shuttle.
它会双面打印  自动装订
It's got, like, double-sided printing, automatic stapling, you know?
认识了许多男的女的  都很友好
Met some nice folks -- guys and gals.
其实就一个女的
Well, gal -- singular, actually.
记住了大家的名字  舔了无数张邮票
Learned everyone's name, and I licked a ton of stamps.
舌头已经像汉堡肉一样了  真的
My tongue is like hamburger meat -- I mean, seriously.
是吧
Yeah?
舌头都舔破了
I got -- thing's raw as hell.
然后才发现有专用的海绵
Then I found out ‭there's a sponge for that.
哎呦  新手错误
Oops! Rookie mistake.
看来你第一周收获挺多嘛
Well, it sounds like you had a very productive week.
是啊  真的很棒
Yeah, it was really great.
我想对你们说
Hey, guys, um...
谢谢你们邀请我做客
Um, I want to thank you for having me over.
这是我十年来吃的最美味的一餐
This is, like, the best meal I've had in a decade.
鱼做得很完美  而且这个
I mean, the fish is perfection, and the, uh...
意大利烩饭
Risotto.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you. That's very kind.
你真是个好厨师
Well, you're a wonderful chef, you know?
不仅是小提琴天赋秉异
Aside from being super talented with the...
你娶了位贤妻  查克  真走运
You got a good one, Chuck -- I mean, lucky, lucky man.
干杯
‭Well, ‭cheers to that.
不好意思
Pardon me.
好了
All right.
吸尘器和摩托车上的律师
What's the difference between a vacuum cleaner
有何不同
and a lawyer on a motorcycle?
吸尘器的尘袋[混蛋]在里面
The vacuum cleaner ‭has the dirt bag on the inside.
律师是坐在外面的混蛋
啊哈  律师笑话
Aha, lawyer jokes.
我才在收发室待了一个星期
I've only been in the mailroom a week,
可能就听了上百个了
and I've heard maybe a hundred.
这都是出于对律师的敬爱
Yeah. ‭It all comes ‭from a place of affection.
当然
Sure. Of course.
把《教父》和律师弄到一起会得到什么
What do you get when you cross the Godfather with a lawyer?
一个你听不懂的提议
An offer you can't understand.
《教父》中有台词"an offer you can't refuse"
此处指律师说的专业术语让人费解
好机灵的笑话
Very clever.
这个没听过
Never heard that one.
相信我
And believe me --
我对你的职业抱有最大的尊敬
I have nothing but the utmost respect for your profession.
这是支柱...
I mean, ‭it's the pillar of -- oh!
为什么要把律师埋在六米深的土下
Why do they bury lawyers under 20 feet of dirt?
因为在内心"深处"  他们其实是好人
Because deep down, ‭they're really good people.
一个智商六十的律师应该叫什么
Uh, w-what do you call a lawyer with an IQ of 60?
"法官大人"
"Your honor."
律师和虱子的区别在哪
What's the difference between a tick and a lawyer?
不
Oh, no.
你死了  虱子就会离开你的身体
The tick falls off when you're dead! Bam!
律师在你死后还会缠着你
好喜欢这个
Love that one.
你喜欢这个吗  我只是开玩笑
You like that? Just joking.
你要知道  我对我的职业是认真的
I want you to know ‭how seriously I take my job.
我真的很感谢  对了
I'm, uh, grateful for the -- oh.
换一个电灯泡要几个律师
How many lawyers does it take to change a light bulb?
这个很经典
Classic setup here.
三个  一个爬梯子  一个摇晃梯子
Three -- one to climb the ladder, one to shake it,
还有一个起诉生产梯子的厂家
And one ‭to sue the ladder company.
很经典
Comedy gold.
-我能说一整晚  -接着说
- I'm here all night! - More. Go, go.
好的  好好好
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
有人要甜点吗
Dessert, anyone?
我们有自己做的蓝莓酥饼配香草冰激凌
We have a homemade blueberry crumble with vanilla ice cream.
蓝莓酥饼  好呀  听起来好棒
Yeah, blueberry crumble -- sounds terrific.
我喜欢有水果的  蓝莓的
I love a fruit-based, uh, blueberry --
-等等  我也想起来一个  -快说
- Wait. I think I know one. - Oh, bring it on.
好啊
Yeah, yeah.
律师和精子的共同点是什么
Um, what do lawyers and sperm have in common?
这个
Oh, just... ‭Um.
三百万  不不
3 million -- no, wait.
三百万分之一
Um, 1 in 3 million...
-有机会成为人类  -有机会成为人类
- have a chance ‭of becoming a human being. - Of becoming a human being.
这个我喜欢
Love that one.
晚餐还不错  你觉得呢
Well, that went well, don't you think?
当然  还是要谢谢你
Sure. Thanks again.
我不知道你在担心什么
I don't know ‭what you were worried about.
吉米挺好的
Jimmy's great.
是挺好的  不  他有点
Yeah. No, he's...
没什么
Yeah.
明天要做什么
So, what's going on tomorrow?
十点要帮戈恩斯泰特作证词
Well, I've got the ‭Gernstetter deposition at 10:00,
午饭后要连开几场合伙人会议
Back-to-back partner meetings after lunch.
应该不会太晚
It shouldn't be a late one.
那女的事情你想得怎么样了
Thought any more about what's-her-name?
那也关系到你的名声  不是吗
It's your reputation, too, you know?
我们周一先从柴可夫斯基开始
Well, we start the Tchaikovsky on monday,
我看看结束时她的状态怎么样
so I'll see what kind of mood she's in when we wrap.
聪明
Smart.
二十五个律师被水泥埋到下巴了  你该说什么
What do you call 25 attorneys buried up to their chins in cement?
-水泥还不够  -什么
- Not enough cement. - ‭What?
绝命律师
第二季 第五集
詹姆斯·麦吉尔
你好  这是金·韦克斯勒的语音信箱
Hello. You've reached the voicemail of Kim Wexler.
请留言
Please leave me a message,
我会尽快回复你
and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
又是我
It's me again.
我想到了一个方法能帮你摆脱那里
Look, I think I found something that could help get you outta there.
我会弥补这一切的
I'm gonna make things right.
给我回个电话吧
Call me, would you?
你好
Hi.
抱歉  我没打算吓你一跳
Sorry. I didn't mean to sneak up on you.
-我以为大家都走了  -没有
- I just thought everyone was gone. ‭- Nope.
我一般都待到很晚
I'm here late most nights.
顺便提一句  我在你办公室看到...
By the way, I noticed in your office...
你扔掉了一个易拉罐
You threw away a soda can.
你翻了我的垃圾
You're going through my trash?
没有
No.
我只是午休时进去送文件
I was just dropping off papers at lunchtime,
无意中看到它在你的垃圾筒里
and I happened to notice it in your trash can.
我把它拿出来了  没事了
I fished it out, so it's fine.
办公室的垃圾筒是扔可回收纸张的
Office cans ‭are for recyclable paper --
厨房里有个单独的大垃圾桶用来放塑料
there's a separate big can in the kitchen for plastic,
玻璃和铝金属
glass, and aluminum.
我们这里十分重视生态足迹
We take our ecological footprint pretty seriously here.
好吧  也就是说
okay, so, the big can
大垃圾桶是扔我的威士忌酒瓶的地方
is where I should throw my empty Scotch bottles.
我明白的
No, I-I get it.
绿色生活
Go green.
好了  还有别的事吗
Good. Was there anything else?
是的  还有一件小事
Yeah, one quick thing.
我这里有你早上给克利福德的简报
I have the brief you gave Cliff this morning --
原告对被告动议的反对
the plaintiff's opposition to the defendant's motion?
我做了几个批注
I have a few notes.
应该挺清楚了
I think they're pretty clear,
但如果我们能一起看一遍可能更好办点
but it's probably easier if we just go over them together.
天啊  那是克利福德的批注
Jesus. Th-those are Cliff's?
不  是我的批注
No, they're my notes.
如果你有时间  咱们现在就过一遍吧
I'd love go to over them now, if you have a minute.
其实没看上去这么糟
It looks worse than it is.
只是...我们有特有的版式
It's -- it's just that we have a particular house style.
无意冒犯
Okay, no offense,
不过  你是两年律师吧
But, uh, you're a second-year associate, right?
-是的  -我有四年了
- Yep. ‭- And I came in as a fourth-year.
没错
That's right.
那为什么一个两年员工要给四年员工做批注
So, why is a second-year giving notes to a fourth-year?
就像我说的  我清楚版式要求
Well, like I said, I know the house style.
是克利福德派你来当我保姆的吗
Does Cliff have you babysitting me?
不是
No.
这只是同事之间互相帮助
This is just one associate helping another.
比如这里  罗马数字标题
Like here, ‭the Roman numeral headings --
全都要大写
we use all caps for those.
你用的是缩进  这当然没问题
And you indented them, which is perfectly fine,
不过克利福德更喜欢居中
but Cliff likes them centered.
差点忘了
Oh, and before I forget,
所有文件中  在句号后面都要空两格
we put two spaces after a period on all our documents.
这的确不是什么大事
I know it seems like a minor thing,
但这样页面会整洁得多
but really looks so much cleaner on the page.
你所做的引述有点多
You went a tad overboard with the quotations.
引用主导性法律意见是没问题的
It's okay to present a quote from a controlling legal opinion,
但如果你引用过多
but when you use too many,
它会打乱你论述的节奏
it disrupts ‭the flow of your argument,
而且让人感觉
and it gives the impression
你没法独立论述
you don't know how to write an argument of your own.
你当然知道怎么写
‭And I'm sure you do, so...
你有过度使用"显然"  "无疑"之类词的倾向
‭You have a tendency to overuse the words "Clearly" and "Obviously."
这其实还是个人见解的问题...
Again, it's a matter of personal opinion --
我真的很感激  艾琳
I really appreciate this, Erin,
但是  我正打算走了
But, uh, ‭I was just on my way out.
我们能不能明天一早再继续讨论
So, if we could continue this first thing tomorrow morning...
我觉得我们应该现在就看完
Well, I was thinking we should just get 'er done now.
分秒必争啊
No time like the present.
当然
Sure.
让我们卷起袖子  大干一场吧
Let's roll up our sleeves and apply a little elbow grease.
太好了
Great!
我去拿我最喜欢的笔
So, I'm gonna get my favorite pen,
随即就去找你
and I will see you momentarily.
没问题
You got it.
韦克斯勒小姐
Uh, Miss Wexler?
你可以叫我金
You can call me Kim.
金  已经十一点四十了
Kim, it's 20 to midnight.
你在问能不能走吗
Are you asking me if you can leave?
伙计们  我又不是你们上司
Guys, I'm not your supervisor.
不用因为我留下来
Don't stick around on my account.
一起走吗  金
You coming, Kim?
随后就走
Right behind you.
只要完成最后这一份
Just finishing up this last one.
斯韦卡特和考科利
又打扰你了  谢了
Again, thanks.
杰苏阿尔多  你今晚可以不打扫吗
Hey, Gesualdo, could you skip vacuuming tonight, please?
就五分钟  就给我五分钟
Five minutes -- just give me five minutes.
这就是解决这场闹剧的方法
Here's how we're gonna handle this travesty of justice.
韦克斯勒诉哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
Wexler vs. Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill --
你想要我起诉我的公司吗
You want me to sue my own firm?
文件都打印好了  蓄势待发
Filing's all typed up. It's ready to go.
这不是我的专长
This is not my area of expertise, all right?
所以首先要做的
So, first order of business --
我们要找一个专门处理劳工法的律师
we get a great employment-law attorney.
让他们知道我们是认真的
Show 'em we mean business.
说真的
‭Come on.
你看看你
Hey, look at you. ‭
你半夜还在这看似荣耀实则监狱的地方
Okay, you're here at midnight in this glorified cellblock
努力工作  是为了什么
busting your ass -- for what?
跟你的表现一点关系也没有
It has nothing to do with your performance.
你受到了不公待遇
You're being mistreated.
查克是通过惩罚你来牵制我
Chuck is punishing you to get to me.
这是敲诈  简单明了
This is extortion, pure and simple.
不  是霍华德要维护形象
No, that's Howard, ‭who has an image to uphold.
凯特尔曼案惨败后他也这么做的
He did the same thing after the Kettleman fiasco,
查克也没有干预
and Chuck was nowhere in sight.
我告诉你  查克就是罪魁祸首
I'm telling you -- Chuck is behind this.
不  你才是罪魁祸首
No, you are behind this.
我告诉过你后果  现在我就在付出代价
I told you this would happen, and now I'm paying the price.
我要是早知道就好了
I shoulda known better.
现在我要保持低调  熬过去
So now I'm keeping my head down, and I'm getting through this.
而且我肯定不会起诉哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所
And I'm most certainly not suing HHM.
-金  -就算我胜诉了  谁还会雇佣我
- Kim - Even if I won, who would hire me?
那是自断前程的行为
That would be career suicide.
好吧
All right.
那我退出戴维斯梅因律所
Then I quit Davis & Main.
那有什么用
What does that accomplish?
这是唯一可以让你脱离困境的方法
It's the only way to get you outta dutch
因为这和查克有关
because this is about Chuck,
不管你信不信
whether you want to believe it or not.
我给他想要的  他就会原谅你
I give him what he wants -- he lets up on you.
我的白马王子
My knight in shining armor.
真是不小的牺牲啊
That is some sacrifice --
辞掉你从一开始就在毁掉的工作
Quitng a job that you've been trying to tank since day one.
不是这样的
That's not true.
我自己想办法脱离困境
I dig myself out of this hole.
你做你的工作  吉米
You do your job, Jimmy.
向我证明你可以做到一周  不  一天
Prove you can go one week -- hell, one day --
不违反新墨西哥律师协会的规则
without breaking the rules of the New Mexico Bar Association
或者不惹你老板生气
or pissing off your boss.
还有不要侮辱我的智商
And don't insult my intelligence
说这么做都是为了我
by saying you are doing any of this for me.
你救不了我
You don't save me.
我才能救自己
I save me.
请你走吧
Just please go.
世上第二棒的律师
艾琳在吗
Hey, is Erin in yet?
该死的烦人鬼
God damn pixie ninja.
实在对不起
I owe you a big apology.
我生了一个病...
I have a medical condition --
胃食管反流病
Gerd, ‭gastroesophageal reflux disease.
我知道  很绕口对不对
I know -- it's a mouthful, right?
它会影响下食道括约肌
It affects ‭the lower esophageal sphincter.
我昨天午餐时冒险吃了些洋葱圈
I took a risk yesterday at lunch with some onion rings,
然后昨晚...
and last night --
我们还要不要工作
Are we doing this or not?
当然
You bet.
杰瑞  我是金·韦克斯勒
Hey, Jerry. It's Kim Wexler.
校友会怎么样了
How's things with the alumni group?
前五十
Top 50?
新墨西哥大学法学院好样的
Go, UNM law!
你有没有听说过圣达菲那边
Hey, wondering if you've heard that Santa Fe place
在寻找新的外聘律师
is looking for new outside counsel.
他们真的应该考虑
They should really be considering
哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所  我们...
Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill. We --
一定是谣言
Must've just been a rumor.
好啊  改天喝一杯
Yeah, let's grab a drink soon.
你也是  好的  再见
You too. Okay, bye.
我记得你提过
Hey, uh, I remember you mentioned
你哥哥曾在英特尔法律部门工作
your brother worked in Intel's legal department.
我是哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的律师
I'm an attorney at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
你知不知道
Would you happen to know
英特尔是否对他们的法律代表满意
if Intel is happy with their legal representation?
我受宠若惊
That's -- that's flattering,
但我已经有男朋友了  所以...
but I'm seeing someone at the moment, so...
这样吧
you know what?
打主机电话  他们会转给我的
Just call the main number, and they'll find me.
好  不  我们几天前喝过了
Yeah, no, we had drinks a few days ago.
她说你有个朋友...
And she said you had a friend who...
所以他们已经解决了
Oh, so they already settled.
我听说你是哈佛法学院的
I heard you ended up at Harvard Law.
对  没错  她是我室友
Yeah, yeah, she was my roommate.
我是哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的律师
Listen, uh, I'an attorney at Hamlin, Hamlin, Mcgill.
我们因与其他律所合作处理大合同而闻名
We're actually known for teaming with other firms on large contracts.
斯韦卡特吗
Schweikart?
当然  我很了解他们  很棒的律所
Sure. Yeah, I know them well. It's a great firm.
我们在去年美国律师协会联谊会上见过
We met at that ABA mixer last year.
没错  波旁酒  就是我
Yep, bourbon shots. That was me.
恭喜你拿下了霍尼韦尔的合同
well, congrats on landing that Honeywell contract --
可不轻松呢
Huge amount of work.
你也是
You, too.
-中午吃得好吗  -不错
- How was your lunch? - ‭Good.
-你吃什么了  -火鸡卷
- What'd you have? - ‭Uh, turkey wrap.
那地方怎么样
How's the place?
很棒
It's great.
安全又安静
It's safe, quiet.
允许狗进入
They allow dogs.
我很满意了
I can't ask for more than that.
凯莉就是不肯出游泳池
I can't get Kaylee out of the pool.
一天结束皮肤准给泡皱
By the end of the day, she's a prune.
她喜欢那儿我真高兴
‭I'm glad she's enjoying it.
我得马上给她准备晚饭了
Hey, I better get her dinner started soon.
下馆子吧
Go to the restaurant.
不  太贵了  屋里有吃的
No, it's too expensive. I have groceries in the room.
不用担心那个
Oh, don't worry about that.
-带她出去  -谢谢  麦克
- Take her out. ‭- Thanks, Mike.
她想你
She misses you.
你一会儿能过来吗
Do you think you might come by later?
还不行
Oh, not yet.
我不想让她看见我这个样子
I don't want her to see me lookin like this.
情况有多糟
How bad was it?
我跟你说  我的下一辆车一定要有气囊
Well, I can tell ya the next car I get's gonna have airbags.
你想什么时候来都行
Well, ‭whenever you feel you're ready.
没关系  看起来比较糟糕而已
Ah, it's okay. ‭It looks worse than it is.
替我亲凯莉一口
You give Kaylee a kiss for me.
我会的
I will.
好的  再见  亲爱的
All right. Bye, darlin.
等等
Hold up.
你怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
我懂  搏击俱乐部的第一条规则是吧
I get it -- the first rule of fight club, right?
给你介绍一下
Uh, let me introduce you.
这是我的保姆  艾琳
This is my babysitter, Erin.
艾琳  这是我的爷爷  麦克
Erin, this is my grandpa, Mike.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
谢了  蒂姆
Thanks, Tim.
很高兴见到你  吉米
Good seein you, Jimmy.
这个职员跟我是老相识了
Listen, this clerk and I go way back.
我俩很铁
We're like this.
但需要施点巧计  所以让我来可以吗
But she needs a little finessing, so can I handle it?
可以啊
Yeah, sure.
惊喜吧
Surprise!
你肯定以为再也见不到我了吧
Bet you never thought you'd see me again.
我需要和布雷诉奥康纳一案的米夏埃利斯
I need a summary judgment hearing
进行简易审判的听证
with Michaelis for Bray v. O'Connell,
希望是周四十点  在他...之前
And I'm hopin for Thursday at 10:00, before he, uh...
没空
Don't have it.
周四十二点呢
Thursday at noon, perhaps?
没有
Nope.
周四下午两点  这是最后...
Thursday at 2:00 -- now, that's my final --
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
你可以做我的新妈妈吗
Will you be my new mommy?
你在做什么
What are you doing?!
-搞什么  -这是贿赂
- What? ‭- That's a bribe.
这是礼物
It's a gift.
在这里就是这么办事的
That's how it works here --
司法之轮需要"润滑"
grease the wheels of justice.
-给我  -不能这样
- Give me -- - That's not how it works.
提交文件  确定日期  就这样
You submit the paperwork, and you get a date -- period.
你懂不懂什么叫略施巧计啊
What don't you understand about finessing?
我为我的同事道歉
I apologize for my colleague.
她是新来的
She's new.
有没有其他办法定个周四的时间呢
Is there any possible way we could still get Thursday?
给你周四下午两点半
I'll give you 2:30 Thursday.
十四号
The 14th.
那是下个月了
That's next month.
好吧就那天
We'll take it.
这会写入我的斯塔西报告吗
So, does this go ‭on my official stasi report?
原东德秘密警察
我这不是给你惹麻烦
I'm not trying to get you in trouble --
而是避免让你惹上麻烦
I'm trying to keep you out of it.
我要上男厕所
I'm gonna hit the men's room.
男厕所
The men's room.
比尔  最近怎么样啊
Hey, how you doing, Bill?
我怎么样  你还好吗
How am I doing? How are you?
勉强过活呗
Oh, you know, hanging in.
听说你去戴维斯梅因律所了
Yeah, word on the street is you're over at Davis & Main now.
你个幸运的混蛋
You lucky son of a bitch.
你知道的  和恶魔共舞
Ah, you know, dancing with the devil.
地检官那里的事情如何...
So, how are things ‭at the district attorney's--
戴维斯梅因
Davis & main!
那铁定很爽吧
Man, that must be sweet!
给你配车了吗
Give you a car?
肯定给你配了车
Bet they gave you a car.
是啊  他们给我配了车
Yeah. They gave me a car.
-什么车  -是一部...
- What kind? - ‭It's a --
停  别告诉我  我不想知道了
No, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
肯定是德国车  是德系的吗
I bet it's German. Is it German?
是德国车
Yeah, it's German.
杯架其实有点...
Uh, the cup holder's actually --
你办公室也很豪华吧
You have a sick office?
肯定特别豪华
I bet you have a sick office.
是很豪华
Pretty sick.
里头还有一个小壁炉
It's got a little fireplace.
壁炉
Fireplace?
为了壁炉我能把我妈杀了
I'd kill my mother for a fireplace.
给我个窗户我也能把她杀了
Hell, I'd kill her for a window.
你还有助理是吧
You, uh, you have an assistant, right?
别告诉我...她很火辣吧
Don't tell me -- is she hot?
她很火辣是吧
She's hot, right?
我的助理是个叫奥马尔的小伙子
She is a bright young man named omar.
奥马尔
Omar.
你衣服上沾了些...
Hey, you got a little something on your, uh...
呕吐物...又来了
That's vomit...again.
最糟糕的是...
The worst part --
可能来自两个不同的被告
Could've come ‭from two different defendants.
人渣  都是人渣
Scumbags. They're all scumbags.
对了  你住哪儿  给你安排住处了吗
Oh, my god. Where you living? They put you up?
我住在公司临租房  就...
It's a corporate apartment. It's just --
停  住嘴
Ah, no, don't tell me.
天呐
Christ.
糟了  我得走了
Ah, damn it. I gotta run.
我要去处理几个白痴...
I'm putting away ‭some brain-dead suck wad...
他们试图抢劫图书馆
who tried to rob a library.
很高兴见到你  比尔
Good seeing you, Bill.
祝你愉快
Have a great day.
走狗屎运的混账
Lucky bastard.
喂  你好
Hello. Hi.
我是金·韦克斯勒
It's Kim Wexler.
我给您留了言  我只是...
I did leave a message, and I was just...
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
抱歉打扰到您了
Sorry to bother you.
你好  我是金·韦克斯勒
Hi. This is Kim Wexler.
我想找卡罗琳·利佩兹
I was looking for Carolyn Lipitz.
不是秘书  我是一名律师
No, not his secretary. I'm an attorney.
是的  克里斯把你的电话给了我
Yes, I did -- I got your number from Chris.
当然  我会给他们说的
Sure. I will let them know.
好的  不  明白了
Okay. Nope, got it.
完全明白
Totally understand.
我是哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的金·韦克斯勒
This is Kim Wexler from Hamlin Hamlin & Mcgill.
其实...我能...
Actually -- hey -- can I just --
你能告诉他我之后再打给他吗
Would you tell him I'll call him right back?
好的  请告诉我什么时候合适
Okay. Just let me know when is a good time.
明白
Got it.
好  打扰您了
Okay. Thanks for your time.
喂  克劳迪娅
Hi, Claudia.
我是金·韦克斯勒
It's Kim Wexler.
我会跟他说的
I'll let him know.
我是金·韦克斯勒
This is Kim Wexler.
我想找吉利安·高根
I was looking for a Jillian Kogan.
去年我在美国律师协会联谊会上认识你的
I met you last year at an ABA mixer.
你知道我恐高
You know I have a fear of heights.
每年夏天都来
Keep coming every summer.
好  有消息的话请跟我说一声
All right, just give me a call. Great.
我是金·韦克斯勒  我昨天打过电话了
Kim wexler. I did call yesterday.
好  我明白了
Okay. I totally get it.
金·韦克斯勒  你还好吗  佩奇
Kim wexler. Hey. How are you, Paige?
是吗
You did?
那...那真是个好消息啊
That's -- that's so nice to hear.
我觉得我们也很合拍呢
I thought we hit it off, as well.
真的吗
Really?
我...
I --
我真的特别激动
I, uh, I-I couldn't be more thrilled.
我是说  律所和我都很激动
It -- I mean, the firm and I.
当然  我现在就跟他说
Absolutely. I'll tell him right now.
明天肯定就能办好...
I'm sure we can get something on the books tomorrow --
最迟后天
Day after, at the latest.
谢谢你  佩奇
Thank you, Paige.
我也是  好  再见
Me, too. Okay, bye.
太好了
Yes!
-她在这儿呢  -你好
- There she is. ‭- Hi.
-你好  -佩奇  很高兴见到你
- Hi. - ‭Paige, so good to see you.
我也是
You, too.
金  这是凯文·沃弛泰尔  公司总裁
Kim, this is Kevin Wachtell, our C.E.O.
我是金·韦克斯勒  很高兴认识你  凯文
Kim Wexler. ‭Great to meet you, Kevin.
我也是
And you.
两位  这是霍华德·哈姆林  高级合伙人
Uh, Paige, Kevin, this is Howard Hamlin, our senior partner.
-很高兴认识你们  -我们也是
- Pleasure. - ‭Likewise.
很高兴你们能来到这里
We're thrilled ‭to have you folks here.
凯文  跟你说个真实的故事  我七岁时
Kevin, true story -- when I was 7 years old,
我的第一个银行账户就在梅萨维德银行
my very first bank account was at Mesa Verde,
你能相信吗
if you ‭can believe it.
我信  我也是  那时我爸还负责经营呢
I can. Mine was, too, back when my dad ran the place.
我记得我第一本存折的封面
I can remember ‭the cover of my first passbook.
-是剪影...  -牛仔的剪影
- It was a silhouette of a... - Cowboy.
马背上的牛仔  站在仙人掌旁边
Cowboy on horseback, yes, standing next to a cactus.
我喜欢那牛仔
I loved that cowboy.
我那时一直在为买下那匹马攒钱
Far as I was concerned, I was saving up for that horse.
不然钱对于一个七岁小孩来说又有什么用呢
What the heck else is money good for when you're 7 years old?
我们在会议室中为你准备了
So, we have ‭a little presentation for you
一次小小的展示  还准备了零食
in our conference room, along with some snacks
和写着你名字的豆奶拿铁
and a soymilk latte with your name on it.
她可真能干
This one -- she's a keeper.
请吧
Shall we?
走吧
Let's do it.
我认为这样再好不过了
Well, I think that ‭couldn't have gone any better.
-很高兴见到你  -棒极了  再见
- Pleasure to meet you. - ‭Fantastic. I'll see you soon.
-感谢你的安排  -再见
- Thanks for setting this up. - Talk to you soon.
很高兴见到你  佩奇
Lovely to meet you, Paige.
恭喜
Congratulations.
同喜
Right back at you.
我之后会和佩奇谈谈  让一切顺利进行
I'll circle back with Paige, get the ball rolling,
开始谈战略
start talking strategy, you know?
或者列个清单  看看派哪些律师去处理
Maybe...put together a list of staff associates we can put on this.
让法兰西斯做吧
I'll put Francis on that.
复审文件已经够你忙的了
You've got enough on your plate in doc review.
来了
Coming.
我来得不是时候吗
Catch you at a bad time?
当然不  进来吧
Not at all. Come in.
我听见叮当声了
I hear clinking.
我们要庆祝什么吗
Does that mean ‭we have something to celebrate?
当然了
We sure do.
我们要庆祝什么
What are we drinking to?
给你弄了个肥差
Got a juicy one for you.
-梅萨维德银行  -预付聘金
- Mesa Verde? - ‭On retainer.
那更好了
Oh, even better.
恭喜
Congratulations.
是你在高尔夫球场上争取到的吗
One of your golf-course conquests?
金·韦克斯勒带来的
Kim Wexler brought them in.
一个四年律师争取到了二十五万的活儿
Fourth-year associate snags a quarter of a million in billings?
她自己可能也在喝酒庆祝呢
She's probably having a couple of drinks herself.
我猜  她应该再次受到重用吧
She's out of the doghouse, I assume?
再说吧
We'll see.
跨州扩张  这案子很复杂
Interstate expansion -- it's a complex case.
我们可能要对付两个  甚至三个监管委员会
That's two, maybe three regulatory commissions we'll be dealing with
律所可能得忙上几个月  甚至几年
Months of work for HHM, maybe years.
早上好  鲁道夫
Good morning, Rudolpho.
早上好  麦吉尔先生
Good morning, Mr. McGill.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我不知道这儿有人
I didn't know anyone was here.
我来送些矶鹞渡的材料
Just dropping off some Sandpiper stuff.
你来早了
You're in early.
其实是待晚了
More like late.
不管现在几点  见到你真高兴
Well, regardless of the hour, good to see you here.
我在做些新尝试
Yeah, ‭I'm trying something new.
我来这一直工作到早九点
I'm coming in, working until 9:00.
律所开门之前办公更容易
It's easier before the place opens,
灯还没亮  电话也不会响个不停
without all the lights and the phones ringing.
想喝点咖啡吗
How about some coffee?
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
那你能帮我泡点咖啡吗
W-would you mind making me some?
对不起
I apologize.
我没法自己做
It's just I-I can't do it myself,
我不能碰电器
what with the electricity.
-好  -不加糖
- Sure. ‭- No sugar.
稍微加点豆奶
Just a splash of soy milk.
应该有
I think we have it.
金
Kim?
泡两杯
Um, make two cups.
他们应该说得对
Well, I guess it's true what they say --
早起的鸟儿有虫吃  如果你喜欢虫子的话
The early bird gets the worm, which is good if you like worms.
我能问个问题吗
May I ask you a question?
当然
Of course.
我在这家律所有前途吗
Do I have a future at this firm?
你我有很多共同点
We have a lot in common, you and I.
我弟弟让你独自承担责任
My brother left you holding the bag.
要知道
If it makes you feel any better,
你不是第一个为他担风险的人
you're not the first person to go out on a limb for him.
我总是反复犯同样的错误
I made the same mistake over and over again.
结果现在霍华德也犯了
And now Howard has...
他怨你
And he blames you.
真是一团乱
It's a damned mess.
吉米跟你说过我们的爸爸的事吗
Jimmy ever tell you anything about our father?
没怎么说过
Not much, no.
我爸爸  我们的爸爸  他是
My dad -- our dad -- he was --
典型的好人
well... the personification of good.
我都不知道他能不能看见任何罪恶
I'm not sure he could even see sin in any form,
他似乎就没这个基因
like he was born without the gene.
他在西塞罗市经营一家街角小店
He ran a little corner store in Cicero --
卖卖烟草  散装糖果
cigarettes behind the counter, penny candy --
没什么特别的  但是能维持家用
nothing special, ‭but it kept food on the table.
邻居们都很喜欢他
And the neighborhood loved dad.
他叫得出每个人的名字  了解他们的生活
He knew everybody's name, what was going on in their lives.
他让这个小小的拐角变得更好
This little corner -- he made it better.
我是以他的名字命名的
I was named after him.
在那之前  他在很多人手下工作过
Before that, he'd worked for a lot of people over the years,
他的梦想就是自己当老板
and his dream was to be his own boss --
倾其所有开了这个小店
put everything he had into that place.
他让吉米在店里干活儿的时候我在外面上大学
I was away at college when he put Jimmy to work there.
吉米从小就在店里  看着爸爸长大
Jimmy grew up in that store, watching our father.
但我爸不善经营
But dad was not the world's greatest businessman,
最终资金周转不灵
and eventually, ‭he ran into money troubles.
那时候我在当法庭书记员
I, um, ‭had a clerkship at the time,
但我还是回家去帮他理清账目
but I came home to help him get his books in order,
解决问题
set the ship straight.
我不是会计
Now, I'm no accountant,
可我还是发现少了一万四千块
but I discovered $14,000 was just gone.
就在这些年里无缘无故消失了
Vanished over the years.
结果是吉米陆陆续续偷的
Turns out Jimmy had pilfered it in dribs and drabs --
直接从收银台拿的
just took it out of the till.
我爸听不进去
My dad wouldn't hear it.
不可能  不是他的吉米干的
Nope. Not his Jimmy.
最后他只能卖了那小店
He ended up having to sell.
半年后  他去世了
Six months later, he was dead.
葬礼上  吉米哭得撕心裂肺
At the funeral, ‭no one cried harder than Jimmy.
我弟弟不是坏人
My brother is not a bad person.
他本性善良
He has a good heart.
只是
It's just...
他控制不住自己
...he can't help himself.
所以只能大家帮他收拾烂摊子
And everyone's left picking up the pieces.
还有咖啡吗
Is there any coffee left?
不  我来吧
No, I got it.
我会跟霍华德谈谈
I'll talk to Howard,
帮你们调解调解
pour a little oil on troubled waters.
让你在下面复审文件太大材小用了
You're being wasted down in doc review.
梅萨维德银行的业务拉得好
Good job with Mesa Verde.
请进  正在营业  今天没活  回家睡觉
我能坐这吗
Mind if I join you?
你好
Hi.
需要点什么吗
What can I get you?
咖啡  清咖
Coffee -- black.
马上就来
Coming right up.
他是把你揍得挺惨的
He really did a number on you.
抱歉  我认识你吗
Sorry. I know you?
打你的那个年轻人
The young man who did that to you.
他是我侄子  一直都这么莽撞
He's my nephew -- ‭hothead, always has been.
以为自己是个拳击手
Kid thinks he's a boxer.
他应该尊重你
He should have shown you respect.
我代表我们全家向你道歉
I apologize to you on behalf of my family.
接受道歉
Apology accepted.
你知道吗
And you know what?
他是该进监狱  这对他再好不过
He should go to jail -- best thing for him.
让他学会尊重长辈
Teach him respect for his elders.
但是  用不着待八年
But... not for eight years --
应该少好几年
less, much less.
你懂我的意思吗
You see what I'm getting at?
不怎么懂
Not really.
非法持有枪支  得判八年  可能十年
The gun charge -- that's 8 years he's going away, maybe 10.
重度攻击  非法持枪  还抢了你的钱包
Aggravated assault, the gun, plus he got your wallet.
没错
That's right.
我希望你能告诉警方
I would like for you to tell the police
枪是你的
that the gun was yours.
是吗
Would you?
他怀疑你撞了他的车
You're both ‭a little hot under the collar
你们俩都没控制住情绪
about whether ‭you bumped his car or not.
你们扭打了起来  然后他抢了你的枪
But there was a scuffle, and, uh, he got your gun.
我的枪
My gun?
他从你的口袋里拿了你的枪
Your gun from your pocket -- he got it,
所以枪上有他的指纹
and that's how his prints got on it.
那我就要面临非法持枪的指控了
And then I'd be subject to the gun charge.
你当过警察
You're an ex-cop.
他们不会为难你
They'll go easy on you.
你还知道别人怎么想啊
So you're a psychic.
我会拧着屠库的耳朵让他给你道歉
I'll even twist Tuco's ear, make him apologize.
他的罪名只有殴打他人  没有其他的了
And he serves for battery -- nothing else.
这结果对大家都是最好的
I'm looking for the best possible outcome for everybody.
至于给你造成的麻烦
And for your trouble...
给你五千块
you take home $5,000.
好好考虑一下
Think about it.